James Simmons papers, 1945-1996
Emory University
- Subject files, 1988-1997, Series 4; Boxes 53-64, OP 5-10
  - Poets' House files, Subseries 4.1; Boxes 53-61; OP 5-9
    - "Poet Not Averse to Boosting Tourist Trade" (Box 61, Folder 15)
    - "Poetic Christmas at Islandmagee," by Neil Johnston in Belfast Telegraph, 24 October 1991 (Box 61, Folder 16)
    - "The Poets' Corner," by Ann Purdy (Box 61, Folder 17)
    - "Poets Find a Home in Falcarragh" (Box 61, Folder 18)
    - "Poets' House Issue Headding Back to Council," in the Times, 7 March 1996 (Box 61, Folder 19)
    - "The Poets' House now in Donegal," in Donegal Democrat, 3 April 1997 (Box 61, Folder 20)
    - "Poets' House Student Lands Major Award," in Larne Times, 1 December 1994 (Box 61, Folder 21)
    - "School's Out as Poet Leaves Ulster Shores," by Neil Johnston (Box 61, Folder 22)
    - "Times Letters," in The Larne Times, 2 May 1996 (Box 61, Folder 23)
    - "Writing on the Wall for Literary School," by Sandra Chapman in Ulster Newsletter, 15 October 1994 (Box 61, Folder 24)
    - Advertisements (Box 61, Folder 25)
    - AIB Better Ireland Awards, 1993 (Box 61, Folder 26)
    - Arts Council-Aer Lingus Travel Awards Brochures (Box 61, Folder 27)
    - Community Relations Council Report 1993 (Box 61, Folder 28)
    - Community Relations in Northern Ireland (Box 61, Folder 29)
    - Lancaster University Department of Creative Writing Handbook (Box 61, Folder 30)
    - Lancaster University Validation Arrangements, Quality Audit Report (Box 61, Folder 31)
    - Miscellaneous Grant Applications (Box 61, Folder 32)
    - Miscellaneous Photocopied Poetry (Box 61, Folder 33)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Material (Box 61, Folder 34)
    - National Lottery Application Form (Box 61, Folder 35)
    - Northern Ireland Structural Funds Plan (1994-1999) (Box 61, Folder 36)
    - Promotional Material (Box 61, Folder 37)
    - The Poets' House 1993 Conferences, Posters (Box OP6)
    - The Poets' House 1994 Conferences, Posters (Box OP7)
    - The Poets' House 1997 Conferences, Poster (Box OP8)
    - The Poets' House Poster, not dated (Box OP9)
    - Relocation Possibilities (Box 61, Folder 38)
    - University of Glamorgan, MA in Writing Handbook (Box 61, Folder 39)
    - University of Glamorgan, Quality and Standards Committee 1993 (Box 61, Folder 40)
    - University of Ulster, Diamond Poets: Joanna Braniff (Box 61, Folder 41)
    - Untitled Newspaper Clippings (Box 61, Folder 42)
  - Other subject files, Subseries 4.2; Boxes 62-64; OP 10
    - Address books (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Aosdána [1 of 2] (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Aosdána [2 of 2] (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Blank postcards (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Campbell College (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Campbell College essays (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Contracts (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Drawings (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Father's Navy documents [1 of 2] (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Father's Navy documents [2 of 2] (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Financial papers [1 of 2] (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Financial papers [2 of 2] (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Hobsbaum Group, photocopies (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Belfast Group Worksheet, Michael Longley: To the Poets, Mountain Swim, A Nativity, Miscarriage, The North, Lares, Caravan (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Belfast Group Worksheet, Paul Muldoon: Wind and Tree, Hedges in Winter, Cuckoo Corn, Siesta, Vampire, Grass Widow, The Indians on Alcatraz, The Electric Orchard (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Belfast Group Worksheet, Paul Muldoon: Wind and Tree, Hedges in Winter, Cuckoo Corn, Siesta, Vampire, Grass Widow, The Indians on Alcatraz, The Electric Orchard (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Belfast Group Worksheet, Watton, Joan: Aunt Alice, Spinster, The Hangover, Detachment, Maggie, Letters from the Island, Wakening [handwritten poem by Gabriel Ferrater on reverse] (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Belfast Group Worksheet, Joan Watton: Betrayal, Gleneyre Children's Home (County Armagh Welfare Committee), An Old Man in a Fish Shop, Worm, Nightmare, A Lone, Middle-Aged, Unmarried Woman Relates, Boyhood Memory (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Belfast Group Worksheet, Paul Muldoon: Blowing Eggs, The Radio Horse, The Field Hospital, On a Dog of Unlike Eyes, The Lost Tribe, The Upriver Incident, Party Piece; [ October 25th 8pm No 4 University Square] (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Belfast Group Worksheet, Philip Hobsbaum: In Retreat (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Belfast Group Worksheet, Seamus Heaney: Servant Boy, The Last Mummer, Gifts of Rain, The Tollund Man, Westering; [ Mon 8th November, 8pm, No 4 University Square] (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Belfast Group Worksheet, Seamus Heaney: Oh Brave New Bull, Mid-Term Break, A Pillar of the Community, MacKenna's Saturday Night, Turkeys Observed, The Indomitable Irishry, Obituary; [handwritten text on the reverse] (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Belfast Group Worksheet, Seamus Heaney: Taking Stock 5/4/`64, Twice Shy, The Early Purges, In Glenelly Valley, Ex-Champ, The Evangelist, Men's Confessions (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Belfast Group Worksheet, Brian Scott: [Untitled], Last Night I wrote a poem of Love, Because I Have a Pact with the Maker, Miracle (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Belfast Group Worksheet, Stewart Parker: Untitled prose (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Belfast Group Worksheet, Stewart Parker: Paddy Dies, Valediction for Hammy from Hangoveria, Inside a Home for the Old, The Broken Lives, Coming Out [2 copies] (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Belfast Group Worksheet, Tom McGurk: September Sibelius, Protest, The Son of the King of Moy, Apologia in Memoriam, Greetings, Mise Eire, Facts of Life ("First-Born," "First-Poem," "First-Sin," "First-Love") (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Belfast Group Worksheet, Bernard MacLaverty: The Choice [short story] (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Belfast Group Worksheet, Maurice Gallagher: Tragrainey [short story] (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Belfast Group Worksheet, Maurice Gallagher: Untitled (Jimmy McHugh was a very quiet person... .) [short story] (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Belfast Group Worksheet, Hugh Bredin: The Kingdom of Heaven [short story] (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Belfast Group Worksheet, Hugh Bredin: Wolf [short story] (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Belfast Group Worksheet, John Bond: Wolf ("Mam") [short story] (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Ibadan Conference (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - John Hewitt Summer School (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - M.A. notes (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous teaching material [1 of 2] (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous teaching material [2 of 2] (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Newry Poetry Competition (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Nigerian Student Poems (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Personal and family items [1 of 2] (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Personal and family items [2 of 2] (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Peterloo Poets 11th Annual Poetry Competition, 1996 (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Recording and song rights (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Research for a book on education [1 of 2] (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Research for a book on education [2 of 2] (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Student essays and comments [1 of 2] (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Student essays and comments [2 of 2] (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Student essays and comments (Box OP10)
- Writings by others, Series 5; Boxes 65-70
  The series includes a variety of manuscripts and typescripts of works by students and other writers. Present are critical writings about Simmons as well as creative work by other writers including: Seamus Heaney, Tony Harrison, John Hewitt, Derek Mahon, Michael Longley, Tess Gallagher, and Wole Soyinka.
  Organized into three subseries: (5.1) Poetry by others, (5.2) Writings about Simmons, and (5.3) Other prose.
  - Poetry by others, Subseries 5.1; Box 65-Box 69
    - By author
    - Anderson, Martin, "Coming From Ulster," TS (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Beer, Patricia, "The Merman," TS (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Blackburn, Thomas, "Hospital for Defectives: Meanwood," TS (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Boyd, Lynsey, "Autumn," MS (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Boyd, Lynsey, "Lovers," MS [See Subseries 5.1, Poetry by Others, Boyd, Lynsey, "Autumn," MS
    - Brophy, Michael, "Dance Little Man," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Brophy, Michael, "Death in the Glen," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Brophy, Michael, "Flowers," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Burleigh, David, "Bird," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Campbell, George, "Apples," TS (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Campbell, George, "Bucolic I," MS (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Cambell, George, "Bucolic II," MS [See Subseries 5.1, Poetry by Others, "Bucolic I"]
    - Campbell, George, "Bucolic III," TS (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Campbell, George, "Christ in Answer to the Soul," MS [See Suberies 5.1, Poetry by Others, "Bucolic I"]
    - Campbell, George, "Epistle," TS [See Subseries 3.1, Uncollected Poetry, "Moonshine Warning"]
    - Campbell, George, "Love Song IV," TS (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Campbell, George, "The Nightingale and the Moon," MS [See Subseries 5.1, Poetry by Others, "Bucolic I"]
    - Campbell, George, "Nursery Rime," MS [See Subseries 3.1, Uncollected Poetry, "Moonshine Warning," and Subseries 5.1, Poetry by Others, "Bucolic I"]
    - Campbell, George, "Rememberance Sunday 1957," MS [See Subseries 5.1, Poetry by Others, "Bucolic I"]
    - Campbell, George, "To Calliope," MS [See Subseries 5.1, Poetry by Others, "Bucolic I"]
    - Campbell, George, "Why Do Men Wrench Their Hearts Awry," TS (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - Cassidy, John, "Love Seen," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Chadbon, John, "The Flood," TS (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - Chadbon, John, "Funeral Rites," TS [See Subseries 5.1, Poetry by Others, Chadbon, John, "The Flood]
    - Cleveland, John, "Newcastle is Peru-Correct Your Maps: Newcastle is Peru!" TS (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - Cooper, Clare, "Sketch," TS (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - Creedy, Arthur, "Rites De Passage," TS (Box 66, Folder 13)
    - Cromie, Stanley, "Philby," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Cromie, Stanley, "Specialization," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Dean, J.S., "From a Friend in Bed to a Poet," MS [See Subseries 3.1, Uncollected Poetry, "To a Friend in Bed from a Poet"]
    - Dibdin, M., "Red Lamps," TS (Box 66, Folder 14)
    - Ellis, Raymond, "Elegy on the Death of Martin Luther King," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Ellis, Raymond, "Yet Another Odyssey," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Ewart, Gavin, "Broadstairs," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Ewart, Gavin, "The Dickens Wife," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Ewart Gavin, "The Seven Stages," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Ewart, Gavin, "A Vision," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Ferre, Leo, "Quartier Latin," TS (Box 66, Folder 15)
    - Fiacc, Padraic, "Morning Dark," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Fiacc, Padraic, "Vengeance," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Fitzmaurice, Gabriel, "The Critic," TS (Box 66, Folder 16)
    - Fitzpatrick, Janice, "The Eater of Butterflies," MSS and TS (Box 66, Folder 17)
    - Fitzpatrick, Janice, "Every Solid Thing," TS (Box 66, Folder 18)
    - Fitzpatrick, Janice, "First Exile," TS (Box 66, Folder 19)
    - Fitzpatrick, Janice, "Hunger," TSS (Box 66, Folder 20)
    - Fitzpatrick, Janice, "Spring 1988," TSS (Box 66, Folder 21)
    - Fitzpatrick, Janice, "Swan Song," TS (Box 66, Folder 22)
    - Friel, Michael, "Gransha," MS and TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Fullerton, D.L., "Euphrasia," TS (Box 66, Folder 23)
    - Fullerton, D.L., "The Peacock Feather," [See Subseries 5.1, Poetry by Others, Fullerton, D.L., "Euphrasia," TS
    - Gallagher, Tess, "Black Valentine," TS (Box 66, Folder 24)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "Blackbird," TS (Box 66, Folder 25)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "Cold Crescent," TS (Box 66, Folder 26)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "Crazy Menu," TS (Box 66, Folder 27)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "Deaf Poem," TS (Box 66, Folder 28)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "Embers," TS (Box 66, Folder 29)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "Fan-shaped Portrait of a Moment's Notice," TS (Box 66, Folder 30)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "Fresh Stain," TS (Box 66, Folder 31)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "Ghost-life of a Ring," TS (Box 66, Folder 32)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "Hairbrushing," TS (Box 66, Folder 33)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "He Would Have," TS (Box 66, Folder 34)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "Magenta Valentine," TS (Box 66, Folder 35)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "Northwest by Northwest," TS (Box 66, Folder 36)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "Now That I Am Never Alone," TS (Box 66, Folder 37)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "Paradise," TS (Box 66, Folder 38)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "Posthumous Valentine," TS (Box 66, Folder 39)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "Quiver," TS (Box 66, Folder 40)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "Rain-soaked Valentine," TS (Box 66, Folder 41)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "Reading the Waterfall," TS (Box 66, Folder 42)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "Sad Moments," TS (Box 66, Folder 43)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "Souvenir," TS (Box 66, Folder 44)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "Strange Thanksgiving," TS (Box 66, Folder 45)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "Thieves at the Grave," TS (Box 66, Folder 46)
    - Gallagher, Tess, "Trace, In Unison," TS (Box 66, Folder 47)
    - Gillian, Pamela, "Come Away," TS (Box 66, Folder 48)
    - Glendinning, Robin, "Goons," TS (Box 66, Folder 49)
    - Gogarty, Oliver St. John, "On First Looking Into Krafft Ebing's Psychopathia Sexualis," TS (Box 66, Folder 50)
    - Gourley, Brian, "Poem for a Twentieth Birthday," TS (Box 66, Folder 51)
    - Gray, Anna, "Stanford Lough," MS (Box 66, Folder 52)
    - Greer, James, "Awakening," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Harrison, Tony, "Allotments," TS (Box 66, Folder 53)
    - Harrison, Tony, "The Flat Dweller's Revolt," TSS (Box 66, Folder 54)
    - Harrison, Tony, "From the Cliffside," TS (Box 66, Folder 55)
    - Harrison, Tony, "From the Sublime, " TS [See Subseries 5.1, Poetry by Others, Harrison, Tony, "From the Cliffside"]
    - Harrison, Tony, "The Pocket Wars of Peanuts Joe," TS (Box 66, Folder 56)
    - Harrison, Tony, "The World's Anatomy," TSS (Box 66, Folder 57)
    - Heaney, Seamus, "Craig's Dragons," TS (Box 66, Folder 58)
    - Heaney, Seamus, "Ocean's Love to Ireland," MS (Box 66, Folder 59)
    - Heard, G.T., "Cocktail Party," TS (Box 66, Folder 60)
    - Hermana, Louise, "Revenant," TS (Box 66, Folder 61)
    - Heath-Stubbs, John, "Epitaph for Thais," TS (Box 66, Folder 62)
    - Hewitt, John, "From the Tibetan," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Hewitt, John, "The Search," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Holland, W.J., "A Short Piece of Friction," MS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Hopwood, J.R.B., "Evensong to the Man-God," TS (Box 66, Folder 63)
    - Kazan, Molly, "Thanksgiving 1963," TS (Box 66, Folder 64)
    - Kennelly, Brenden, "Birthdays and Farewells," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Kennelly, Brenden, "A Couple," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Kennelly, Brenden, "A Man in Yellow Oilskin," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Kennelly, Brenden, "The Stones," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Lathum, J, "James Simmons Sings Yeats," TS (Box 66, Folder 65)
    - Lavery, Leo, "April," TS (Box 66, Folder 66)
    - Lavery, Leo, "November," TS (Box 66, Folder 67)
    - Lavery, Leo, "Poetic Complaint," TS (Box 66, Folder 68)
    - Lavery, Leo, "A Xmas Poem," TS (Box 66, Folder 69)
    - Leonard, "Words and Words," TSS (Box 66, Folder 70)
    - Lewis, Peter, "A Tale of a Turd," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Long, Declan, "Artists," TS (Box 66, Folder 71)
    - Long, Declan, "At Portstewart Strand, Co. Antrim," TS (Box 66, Folder 72)
    - Long, Declan, "Biography of a Dry Patch," TS (Box 66, Folder 73)
    - Long, Declan, "Saying Goodbye to Maria," TS (Box 66, Folder 74)
    - Long, Declan, "Underneath Language," TS (Box 66, Folder 75)
    - Longley, Michael, "Spells," MS (Box 66, Folder 76)
    - Mahon, Derek, "Beyond Howth Head," TS (Box 66, Folder 77)
    - Mahon, Derek, "A Dying Out," MS and TS [See also Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman] (Box 66, Folder 78)
    - Mahon, Derek, "Ecclesiastes," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Mahon, Derek, "Fall-Out," MS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Mahon, Derek, "The Graduation in Metal Bose," MS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Mahon, Derek, "Tragic Hero of Our Time," MS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Mahon, Michael, "March," TS (Box 66, Folder 79)
    - Marno, David Cajeton, "Autumn Ventures," TS (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Marno, David Cajeton, "Mountain Prospect," TS [See also Subseries 5.1, Poetry by Others, Blackburn, Thomas, "Hospital for Defectives: Meanwood"] (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Marno, David Cajeton, "Poem on a Mobile. A Wire Guitarist," TS [See Subseries 5.1, Poetry by Others, Blackburn, Thomas, "Hospital for Defectives: Meanwood"]
    - Marshall, Jon, "The Poet's Daughter," TS (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Martin, Hazel, "Folk Song," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Martin, Hazel, "Magilligan," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - McAvoy, WG, "Defeat-A Dream," MS (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - McAvoy, WG, "Frustration," MS (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - McAvoy, WG, "Invitation from the Gods," MS (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - McClosky, Phil, "A Poetic Interlude of Lake Isle Readings," TS (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - McEneaney, Kevin T., "Eating the Worm," TS (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - McEneaney, Kevin T., "The Pure of Heart Shall Inherit the Earth," TS (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - McFeeter, Gerry, "Poem for the Womanhood of Today," MS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - McKittrick, David, "A Soliloquy for a Painter," TS (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - McKittrick, Evelyn, "Blue," TS (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - McKittrick, Evelyn, "The Bones of Belfast," TS (Box 67, Folder 12)
    - McKittrick, Evelyn, "The First Time," TS (Box 67, Folder 13)
    - McKittrick, Evelyn, "Into the Dark," TS (Box 67, Folder 14)
    - McKittrick, Evelyn, "Poetry is an Amputee," TS (Box 67, Folder 15)
    - McKittrick, Evelyn, "Retribution," TS (Box 67, Folder 16)
    - McKittrick, Evelyn, "Second Death," TS (Box 67, Folder 17)
    - McMahon, Lynne, Devolution of the Nude, TS (Box 67, Folder 18)
    - McPhee, Kenneth, "Ana Cristina Martins Da Costa," TS (Box 67, Folder 19)
    - McPhee, Kenneth, "But You Love Are a Moth!," TS (Box 67, Folder 20)
    - McPhee, Kenneth, "Down There Somewhere!," TS (Box 67, Folder 21)
    - McPhee, Kenneth, "God's Teardrops," TS (Box 67, Folder 22)
    - McPhee, Kenneth, "In the Great Library," TS (Box 67, Folder 23)
    - McPhee, Kenneth, "Kind Hearts," TS (Box 67, Folder 24)
    - McPhee, Kenneth, "Les Enfants Du Paradis," TS (Box 67, Folder 25)
    - McPhee, Kenneth, "Psyche Needs Explaining," TS (Box 67, Folder 26)
    - McPhee, Kenneth, "Small People Stop Me!," TS (Box 67, Folder 27)
    - McPhee, Kenneth, "Snail-Slow," TS (Box 67, Folder 28)
    - McPhee, Kenneth, "Sweating Tears, Crying Sweat," TS (Box 67, Folder 29)
    - Michie, James, "The Martial," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - Middleton, Kate, Kate Middleton Poems, TS (Box 67, Folder 30)
    - Morris, Margery, "A Grader on Sunday," TS (Box 67, Folder 31)
    - Moya, Carmela, "Grandfather Clock," TS (Box 67, Folder 32)
    - Muldoon, Paul, "Hedgehog," MS (Box 67, Folder 33)
    - Newmann, Joan, "Lindy on the Island of Roses," MS (Box 67, Folder 34)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "And Andrew Waterman," TS (Box 67, Folder 35)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Angels," TS (Box 67, Folder 36)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Anne-Marie," TS (Box 67, Folder 37)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "April Moon," TS (Box 67, Folder 38)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Castles in the Air," TS (Box 67, Folder 39)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "The Coal Lagoon," TS (Box 67, Folder 40)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Colleen's Man," TS (Box 67, Folder 41)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Decisions," TS (Box 67, Folder 42)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Delicate Cradle," TS (Box 67, Folder 43)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Eoghain," TS (Box 67, Folder 44)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Footballs," TS (Box 67, Folder 45)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Ghosts of Comrades Past," TS (Box 67, Folder 46)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "God Always Wore a Butcher's Apron," TS (Box 67, Folder 47)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Gulags," TS (Box 67, Folder 48)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Judge Allswell," TS (Box 67, Folder 49)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "KC Identity," TS (Box 67, Folder 50)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Kevin McKearney," TS (Box 67, Folder 51)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Letter to a Bishop," TS (Box 67, Folder 52)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Letters," TS (Box 67, Folder 53)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Love and Beauty Saves the World," TS (Box 67, Folder 54)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Lucy's Yarn," TS (Box 67, Folder 55)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Maghaberry," TS (Box 67, Folder 56)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Medbh's Electric Blue," TS (Box 67, Folder 57)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Michael James, Anthem," TS (Box 67, Folder 58)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Murdering a Mansion," TS (Box 67, Folder 59)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "New Years '93," TS (Box 67, Folder 60)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "News in Brief," TS (Box 67, Folder 61)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Night at the Opera," TS (Box 67, Folder 62)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "The Piccasso Shirt," TS (Box 67, Folder 63)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "A Private Affair," TS (Box 67, Folder 64)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Questions of History," TS (Box 67, Folder 65)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Rabbit Island," TS (Box 67, Folder 66)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Shell Place," TS (Box 67, Folder 67)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Silver and the Cross," TS (Box 67, Folder 68)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Silver Birch Tree," TS (Box 67, Folder 69)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Slan Mo Mhathair," TS (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Smile Sorrow," TS (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Stone Room," TS (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "To Jimmy Simmons," TS (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Touch Rekindle," TS (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Two Rebels," TS (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "Who Don't Know They Don't Know," TS (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - O'Conghalaigh, Tarlac, "You and Whose Army," TS (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - O'Connor, Fleann, "Salvage," TS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]
    - O'Grady, Desmond, "Belfast Bedroom," TS (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - O'Kelly, Dominic, "Sir Frederick Simmons," TS (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - O'Kelly, Jon, "Maximum Content and Minimum Hered," MS [See Subseries 3.6, Works Edited by Simmons, The Honest Ulsterman]